title: Odczasownikowe rzeczowniki
slug: polish-odczasownikowe-rzeczowniki
description: Rzeczowniki odczasownikowe w języku polskim
maxQuestions: 20
questions:
  - question: "analizować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "analizowanie"

  - question: "badać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "badanie"

  - question: "bić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "bicie"

  - question: "biegać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "bieganie"

  - question: "brać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "branie"

  - question: "budować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "budowanie"

  - question: "być"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "bycie"

  - question: "cofnąć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "cofnięcie"

  - question: "ćwiczyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "ćwiczenie"

  - question: "czyścić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "czyszczenie"

  - question: "czytać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "czytanie"

  - question: "dać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "danie"

  - question: "decydować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "decydowanie"

  - question: "gotować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "gotowanie"

  - question: "jeść"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "jedzenie"

  - question: "jeździć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "jeżdżenie"

  - question: "koncentrować się"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "koncentrowanie się"

  - question: "kończyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "kończenie"

  - question: "kontrolować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "kontrolowanie"

  - question: "kryć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "krycie"

  - question: "kupować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "kupowanie"

  - question: "lać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "lanie"

  - question: "łączyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "łączenie"

  - question: "leczyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "leczenie"

  - question: "mówić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "mówienie"

  - question: "myć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "mycie"

  - question: "myśleć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "myślenie"

  - question: "negocjować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "negocjowanie"

  - question: "niszczyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "niszczenie"

  - question: "odkrywać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "odkrywanie"

  - question: "odpoczywać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "odpoczywanie"

  - question: "odrzucić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "odrzucenie"

  - question: "oglądać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "oglądanie"

  - question: "organizować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "organizowanie"

  - question: "osiągać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "osiąganie"

  - question: "otworzyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "otworzenie"

  - question: "palić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "palenie"

  - question: "pić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "picie"

  - question: "pisać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "pisanie"

  - question: "planować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "planowanie"

  - question: "podróżować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "podróżowanie"

  - question: "połączyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "połączenie"

  - question: "poprawiać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "poprawianie"

  - question: "porównywać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "porównywanie"

  - question: "pracować"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "pracowanie"

  - question: "prowadzić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "prowadzenie"

  - question: "przeżyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "przeżycie"

  - question: "przygotowywać się"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "przygotowywanie się"

  - question: "przyjąć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "przyjęcie"

  - question: "robić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "robienie"

  - question: "rozwiązywać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "rozwiązywanie"

  - question: "rozwijać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "rozwijanie"

  - question: "skupiać się"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "skupianie się"

  - question: "słuchać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "słuchanie"

  - question: "spełnić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "spełnienie"

  - question: "spotkać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "spotkanie"

  - question: "spotykać się"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "spotykanie się"

  - question: "sprzątać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "sprzątanie"

  - question: "sprzedawać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "sprzedawanie"

  - question: "szyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "szycie"

  - question: "tłumaczyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "tłumaczenie"

  - question: "tworzyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "tworzenie"

  - question: "uczestniczyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "uczestniczenie"

  - question: "uczyć się"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "uczenie się"

  - question: "użyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "użycie"

  - question: "wybierać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "wybieranie"

  - question: "zabić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "zabicie"

  - question: "zaczynać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "zaczynanie"

  - question: "zamknąć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "zamknięcie"

  - question: "zapewnić"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "zapewnienie"

  - question: "zapraszać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "zapraszanie"

  - question: "zarządzać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "zarządzanie"

  - question: "zastanawiać się"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "zastanawianie się"

  - question: "znać"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "znanie"

  - question: "zniszczyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "zniszczenie"

  - question: "żyć"
    type: text-input
    correctAnswer: "życie"
